Total Experience: 1 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Notice Period: 1 Month

Engineering]



OCA Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, J2EE, Spring Framework, Microservices, Maven, GIT, Splunk, JIRA, Oracle, MySQL, SQL Server



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer -Java/J2EE

Current Company: CAPGEMINI India Pvt Ltd,

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Project

Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, J2EE, Spring Framework, Maven, GIT, JIRA, Oracle, MySQL, SQL Server, Microservices

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

### **Summary**

Java Full stack developer with 20 months of experience and award-winning performance in Java, Spring Boot, REST API, Microservices, Selenium and so on. Have worked across the banking domain. Hands on experience in development of financial and banking products and have delivered various solutions. Enthusiastic and flexible engineer who is ready to learn new technologies and to face complex challenges.

Strengths: Positive Attitude, Technical and analytical skills, leading skills, ability to work under high pressure.

# **Work Experience**

CAPGEMINI India Pvt Ltd, as Senior Software Engineer -Java/J2EE

Jan 2019 to Till Date

Hong Kong Shanghai Banking Corporation (HSBC)

Experience of working as a developer in HSBC Wealth Management developer team.

Played many responsibilities like software design and development along with closely analyzing the client needs.

Worked on the development of the various microservices of the web application using Spring boot REST, Microservices and JPA-Hibernate.

Hands-on experience on terraform to build AWS infrastructure.

Cooperate diligently with other IT team members to plan, design, and develop smart solutions and understand the needs of client.

Played a key role in Scrum ceremonies such as sprint planning and story grooming etc.

Have led 3 people for the completion of various big tasks.

Have used various development tools like GIT, Jenkins, Postman to support the development process.

Have written feature files using gherkin for all the user stories developed to assist the testing team.

Technology Stack-: Java, J2EE, Spring boot (REST, Microservices), Maven, GIT (Bit-Bucket), IntelliJ, SQL, JPA-Hibernate, Eureka Server, Jenkins, AWS, Terraform.

Software Engineer - (06/2019 -06/2020)

CAPGEMINI India Pvt Ltd, Pune

(French multinational corporation that provides consulting, technology, professional, and outsourcing services)

Morgan Stanley Fund Services (Global Reconciliation)

Experience of working as a developer in MSFS (Global Reconciliation) developer team.

Played many responsibilities like software design and development along with closely analyzing the client needs.

Worked on the development of the various web services in the web application using Spring boot REST, Microservices and JPA-Hibernate

Hands-on experience on SQL to write PI/SQL queries.

Worked on Automation development (Front-end testing and back-end testing) using selenium and java and SOAP of the same product.

Cooperate diligently with other IT team members to plan, design, and develop smart solutions and understand the needs of client.

Played a key role in Scrum ceremonies such as sprint planning and story grooming etc.

Technology Stack-: Java, J2EE, Spring boot and REST, Microservices, Selenium, Maven, GIT (Bit-Bucket), IntelliJ, SQL, JPA-Hibernate, Eureka.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS-:**

Awarded as Star Employee of Month to quickly adapt technologies for the development of product and bug-free deliveries to the client.

Awarded as Innovative Brain of Month from the client for the best idea to business problem.

INTERN Java Full Stack (01/2019 - 04/2019)

CAPGEMINI India Pvt Ltd, Pune

Trained on Java technologies Spring (Core, Boot, Rest), JPA-Hibernate, Selenium, Gherkin, maven for 3 months Worked at Internal Project (Social media application) along with 3 other persons as a team

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Chandigarh University in 2019

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

**Oracle Certified Associate** 

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JAVA, J2EE			
SPRING FRAMEWORK			
Rest API, Boot, Microservices			
SELENIUM			
MAVEN			
GIT, Splunk			
JIRA, Eureka Netflix Server			
ORACLE, MYSQL			
SQL Server			
Tomcat 8			
Windows 7/10			
AWS, Terraform			

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak

1/22/2021	https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=429f4315a78a8f48a3d8053d2be33e135d585a5542425	5f120747170e0e
English		

English	
Hindi	

# **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

# **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time